Eddie Fernandez

 $19803\ 15$ th Ave E, Spanaway, WA $98387\ |\ 253\text{-}507\text{-}3193\ |\ fernandezeddie 54@gmail.com\ |\ www.linkedin.com/in/EddieFernandezDev$

Profile

Software developer with a year of experience working remotely at startup tech company Lowkel. Studied applied mathematics and economics in college. Capable of creating, developing, testing, and deploying software and models designed to improve business operations.

Education

Bachelor's Degree | Washington State University | August 2016 - May 2020

- Major: Applied Mathematics, Minor: Economics (3.2 GPA)
- Completed Courses: Calculus, Differential Equations, Mathematical Optimization, Real Analysis, Mathematical Computing, Data Structures C/C++, Program and Design C/C++, Statistics, Linear Algebra and Econometrics

Experience

Software Developer | Interco.ai | 05/2022 - Current

- Created a demo web page that showcases 3D models in augmented reality using WebXR model viewer.
- Created an immersive AR webpage that utilizes hit tests to create objects in AR environments that can be accessed on android and IOS.
- Developed an interactive mobile web page designed to teach new restaurant employees how
 to assemble the ingredients of a burger. Used THREE.JS to render the 3d model of the burger
 and its ingredients.
- Developed a 3d third person shooter minigame demo using THREE.JS which can be played on a web browser.

Security Officer | Allied Universal | 05/2022 - Current

- Greeted and maintained good relations with employees entering the warehouse facility
- Utilized wands and metal detectors to screen employees for any stolen merchandise
- Approached incidents in a calm and professional manner

Software Developer | Lowkel | 04/2021 - 12/2021

- Developed software written in python to predict and optimize Lowkel delivery driver route pathing, timing, and cost.
- Created software written in JavaScript using MongoDb to correct product data at scale.
- Improved Lowkel app site search accuracy by 50% by implementing multi word query processing, stop words, result relevancy system, fuzzy search, typo correction using levenshtein distance, and search keyword tags.
- Reduced site search result processing time from 10 seconds to 1 second
- Improved Lowkel phone app design through quality assurance testing.

E-Commerce Manager | Swift Sales | 01/2018 - Current

- Sold collectible trading cards through TCGplayer online store front.
- Analyzed, organized, and collected business sales data and managed using spreadsheets and self-developed software.
- Created predictive models to estimate time, cost, and profit for buying, selling, sorting, and shipping inventory.
- Improved sorting methods and purchase methods by conducting market research.

Skills

- Proficient with Python, JavaScript, Java, C#, C++, Git, MongoDB and Mongoose, Node JS, Site Search, Google maps API, Stata, R, MATLAB, Octave, OOP, Entity Component Systems, Machine Learning, Database structures and algorithms.
- Excellent communication, curiosity, adaptability, critical thinking, team driven skills, and problem-solving abilities, pattern recognition.